Guide to the New-York Historical Society Schenectady Collection 1688?-1883, undated (bulk, 1710s-1840s) MS 544
New-York Historical Society
- Articles of Agreement, 1780 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Agreement between Cornelius DeGraaf and Deacons of Reformed Protestant Dutch Church regarding a grist mill.
- Order, 1780 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Order for John Empie to immediately deliver goods belonging to persons of Tryon County who have joined the enemy to Colonel John Carpor signed by Hugh Mitchell Garten.
- Receipt, 1781 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Receipt signed by Henry Glen and Andrew Rynes, John Empie and John Crowshorn.
- Indenture, 1782 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Yearly rent between Thomas Hall and Ryer Schermerhorn.
- Indenture, 1782 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letter, 1782 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Letter to Jeremiah Van Renselear, Paymaster to the N.Y. Regiment, from Henry Glen regarding piece of linen for shirting.
- Receipt, 1783 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Receipt between John Empie and Abraham Brimershoff.
- Promise to pay, 1784 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Promise to pay to John Lyon by John Empie.
- Receipt, 1784 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Receipt between John Empie and Jacob Ten Eyck.
- Promise to pay, 1785 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Promise to pay to Barrent C. Ten Eyck by Benjamin Springer.
- Invoice sheet, 1786 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  1786 John Empie Invoice Sheet.
- Receipt, 1786 January 26 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Receipt between John Keyser and Jacob Beekman.
- Invoice sheet, 1786 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  John Empie's Invoice sheet for Jacobus N. Slych.
- Promise to pay, 1786 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Promise to pay to John Nellis by John Empie.
- Certificate, 1786 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Certificate that Jeremiah Romeyer has studied Natural and Moral Philosophy and Natural and Revealed Theology and will be useful to the Church of God.
- Order to lay out highway (copy for record), 1786 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Highway beginning at John Sanders' Mill Road and heading westerly ordered by Commissioners: Louis Van Patten; Cornelius Van Dyck; Jacob Schermerhorn (Commissioners of Public Highways for the District of Schenectady).
- Promise to pay, 1786 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Promise to pay to Jacob Vrooman by John Empie.
- Promise to pay, 1786 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Promise to pay by John Empie.
- Promise to pay, 1786 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Promise to pay to Henry Staats by John Empie.
- Promise to pay, 1786 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Promise to pay to Benjamin Evans by James and Thomas Lewis Van Patten.
- Invoice sheet, 1787 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  John Empie's Invoice sheet of Maria Hall and of Mr. Clerk.
- Contract of Sale, 1787 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Sale of 47 year old African-American man, named Jule, by David Lucy to Johannis Becker.
- Note, 1787 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Note asking to send along what was discussed by bearer signed by John Empie directed to Mr. Sisher.
- Letter, 1787 August 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Letter from distressed creditor, G.C. Stocker, whose silver shoebuckles were taken as repayment of 15 shillings, to John Empie.
- Promise to pay, 1787 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Promise to pay to Eldert Ament signed by Cathrina Empie.
- Receipt, 1787 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Receipt between John Empie and Peter Van Guysling.
- Promise to pay, 1788 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Promise to pay to Joseph Johnson by John Empie.
- Receipt, 1788 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Receipt between John Empie and Alexander Mercer.
- Note, 1788 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Note regarding payment of indebtedness between John Empie and Laurence Mynderse.
- Invoice to pay, 1788 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Invoice to John Empie from John Van Sic (?) to please pay Mr. Cardiff (?)
- Receipt, 1788 December 13 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Receipt from Robert H. Windall to John Empie.
- Letter, 1789 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Letter to Mr. Patrick Cannaday from John Flagg regarding performing your bargain in our agreement.
- Demand for Payment, 1789 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Abraham Swits demands just payment from John Empie.
- Indenture, 1789 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Involving Parcels of land along side Mohawk River, northwesterly of Schenectady, between Gerrit Lansing; Jacobus Mynerse; Reyer Wimple; Samuel Bradt; Nicholas Van Patten; Abraham Fonda; Harmanus Bradt; Isaac Vroman; Nicholas Van de Vogle; Abraham Wimple (Trustees for the Township of Schenectady) and John B. Winsell.
- Note, 1789 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Note to send 5/6 pounds in cash by the bearer by Lawrence Vrooman to John Sanders.
- Demand for payment, 1789 November 26 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Letter from Abraham Swits to John Empie Pay or "elce exspect troubel".
- Account, 1791-1793 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Account of Philip Wendell to John Searles & Co.
- Letter, 1791 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Letter from Abraham Fonda; Harmanus Bradt (Trustees of Schenectady) requesting any papers from John Sanders that could offset Schermerhorn's claims.
- Petition, 1792 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Petition regarding southern boundary of Schenectady between citizens of Schenectady and House Assembly.
- Receipt, 1793 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Receipt from Richard Edsall, surveyor,for payment for surveying Great Island in the Mohawk River (now, Shakers Island) by order of James W. Wilkin.
- Letter, 1795 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Letter to John Sanders from Van Ingen; Van der Howell regarding $800 note.
- Lease, 1796 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Yearly lease for house and land between John Sanders and David Luyport.
- Account book (24 pages), 1796 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Account book of round trip passage from Schenectady to Montreal. Received 9 dollars from Simon T. Toll for passage.
- List of Members of Highway Commission, 1798 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  13 names
- List of Names, 1798 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  13 names of persons of Schenectady.
- Indenture (Incomplete), 1798 January 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Indenture (Incomplete) regarding parcel lying on south side of Mohawk River between Abraham Wemple; Nicholas Veeder; Gerrit S. Veeder, Jr.; John Glen; John Sanders; Abraham Oothout; Abraham Swits; Jellis Fonda; Andries Van Patten; Adam S. Vrooman; Richard Schermerhorn (Trustees of the Town of Schenectady) and no second party given.
- Letter, 1798 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Letter from Committee of Correspondence, Schenectady, to John Sanders regarding nomination as candidate for Office of Senator.
- Bill for Service, 1798 April (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Bill for Service of Joseph Peck; Francis Veeder; Jacob G. Fonda as inspectors of the election.
- Bill for Service, 1798 April (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Bill for Service of Simon J. Van Antwerp; Maus Schermerhorn; Abraham P.Truax as inspectors of the election.
- Bill for Service, 1798 April (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Bill for Service of Isaac de Graas; Herman Vedder; Alexander McMichael as inspectors of the election.
- Bill for Service, 1798 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Bill for Carpentry Service of Omer Boden to John Sanders.
- Invoice, 1798 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Invoice to Mr. Combs.
- Draft Letter, 1799 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Unsigned draft letter to the Albany Gazette regarding damage to my reputation of a man of veracity.
- Draft Letter, 1799 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Dispute between Mr. John Sanders and Mr. Van Vechter.
- Minutes of Meeting, 1799 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Meeting of the Citizens of the 4th Ward of the City of Schenectady regarding nomination of candidates.
- List of Names, 1799 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Names of Freeholders of the City of Schenectady entitled to serve as jurymen
- Resolution, 1799 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Resolution of Common Council to raise sum of $280 dollars for cost of night watch.
- Account, 1800 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Account of Abraham Hoffman from George Sperlinge.
- Deposition, 1800 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Deposition of William Adams regarding sale of house by Joseph Shurtleff, auctioneer.
- Account, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Account of Benjamin Goodrich by Capt. Richard Duncan.
- Petition, 1801 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Petition Citizens of the 4th Ward of the City of Schenectady to name John Lighthall Justice of the Peace for 4th ward directed to the Council of Appointments.
- Letter, 1802 January 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Letter from Jacob Mabee to John Sanders regarding Assessor's certificate.
- Memorandum of Agreement, 1802 February (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Memorandum of Agreement between Jacob Osbourne and John Sanders regarding Ferry on Mohawk River.
- Agreement, 1802 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Agreement between Jacob Osbourne and John Lighthall regarding Ferry on Mohawk River.
- Inventory, 1803 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 13Inventory)
  Inventory by Jacob and Cornelius Becker of clothing.
- List of names, 1805-1808 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  List of names - some sort of account
- Survey, 1805 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Survey of land of Jacob Nehrs near turnpike road to Schenectady.
- Agreement, 1806 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Agreement on Lease and Management of Ferry service on Mohawk River between John Sanders and Simon J. Toll.
- Letter (copy), 1806 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Letter (copy) to Corporation of Schenectady from John Sanders regarding Ferry service.
- Letter, 1807 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Letter from Corporation of Schenectady to John Sanders regarding Ferry service.
- Letter (copy), 1807 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Letter from J. (John Sanders - not signed) to Corporation of Schenectady regarding Ferry service.
- Resolution, 1807 September 25 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Resolution by Directors of the Mohawk Turnpike Company regarding no compensation for John Sanders as director.
- Deposition, 1808 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Deposition of Thomas Gooseberry regarding ferry service.
- Deposition, 1808 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Deposition of John S. Ten Eyck regarding ferry service.
- License, 1808 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Ferry License for John Sanders.
- Invoice, 1808 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Invoice between Jacob and Mathais Shears and R. Wamsley.
- Invoice, 1809 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Invoice between George Taylor and R. Wamsley.
- Invoice, 1809 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Invoice from John Sanders to Benjamin Arkins for a harness.
- Muster Roll, 1809 August (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Muster Roll at Dock of Court Street
- List of names, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  List of names of Persons owing John Sanders for ferriage.
- List of names, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Names of Candidates (printed)
- Petition, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Petition by the Citizens of the 4th Ward of the City of Schenectady to the Legislature of New York regarding highways in 4th Ward.
- Petition, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Petition of Volkert Veeder to the Legislature of New York stating he is owner of a Ferry on the northside of the Mohawk River.
- Receipt, 1810 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt between Henry Bansler and Joseph Shorp.
- Receipt, 1810 May 31 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt between Henry H. Wendell and Brown & Tripp.
- Letter, 1810 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Letter to Henry Wendell, Esq. from Anson Brown (attorney for H. Benedict) regarding collection of money.
- Receipt, 1810 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt for house and lot on Dock Street signed by Christopher Beekman.
- Payment Order, 1811 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Order signed by William J.M. carter for bearer to pay $3.56 to W. Calvin Dodge.
- Receipt, 1812 March 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt between Smith & Chase and Henry R. Wendell.
- Receipt, 1812 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt between Henry R. Wendell and John Prouty.
- Payment Order, 1815 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Order signed by Shubat Reynolds for bearer to pay $8.28 to Abraham Master.
- Promissory Note, 1815 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  A promise signed by Jacob R. Wendell to pay $30 to Constables.
- Account, 1816-1817 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Account of Robert Brown to H.R. Wendell.
- Lease, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Use of home in 1816 between Jerome Barhyth and Nathan Barnet.
- Account, 1816 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Account for timber bought between George Cooper and Henry Wendell.
- Conveyance, 1816 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Conveyance of a right to a steam engine patent between Abraham Dudley and Ebenezer Belknap.
- Warrants, 1817-1819 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  49 warrants signed by W.R. Wendell, Justice of the Peace.
- Receipt, 1817 January 28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt of William Benedict.
- Receipt, 1817 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt of Eliza Anderson
- Payment Order, 1817 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Order signed by Robert Kelly for bearer to pay $3.50 to Peter Walker.
- Receipt, 1817 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt between H.R. Wendell and H.H. Ten Eyck.
- Receipt, 1817 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt between Mr. Wendell and Hugh Con Wright.
- Receipt, 1817 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt between Joseph Waukins and Peter Branaghin.
- Indenture, 1817 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Lease of tavern stand between John Sanders and Enock Willard.
- Receipts, 1817 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipts signed by Jacob Swits, Church Treasurer, to Consistory of Dutch Church.
- Court Document, 1818 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Document in the case of Joseph Lawrence v. Freeman Vrooman.
- Bill, 1818 February 5 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Bill of School District No. 3 to H.R. Wendell.
- Jury Summons, 1818 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Summons for jury in case of trespass between Peter Branaghin and Jellis Fonda.
- Warrant, 1818 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Warrant to apprehend Shubat Renalds and Briny Limfar for Trespass upon Solomon Homes.
- Warrant, 1818 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Warrant to apprehend Shhubat Renalds for Trespass upon Adam Van Voast.
- Warrant, 1818 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Warrant for Trespass by Peter DuBois upon Solomon Homes.
- Receipt, 1818 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt between Henry Wendell and Peter McDougall.
- Receipt, 1818 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt between James Thompson and John Caton.
- Promissory Note, 1818 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  A promise signed by James Barhyath to pay $25 to Jesse Barhyth.
- Warrant, 1818 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Warrant to apprehend John Earls for assault on Thomas Bohanen.
- Warrant, 1818 December 26 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Warrant to apprehend Bartholomew Van Allen for assault on Mathais Bramen.
- Court Document, 1819 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Document in the case of Nathan Benet v. Geronamos Barhyth.
- Receipt, 1819 January 5 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt of the Trustees of the School District
- Resolution, 1819 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Resolution made by Aged Farmers of 3rd/4th Ward of Schenectady for Legislature to pass law that 3rd/4th Wards incorporated separately.
- Diary Entries of the Weather, 1819 February (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Entries regarding weather in February 1819.
- Collection of School Tax, 1819 March 29 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Receipt for collection of tax for the second school district of Schenectady.
- Plat, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Plat shows land parcel between Union, Ferry, Watton Streets and Osbourne Lot. Plat is part of legal case in Superior Court, Sarah Hosford and others v. Jonathan Wallon.
- Court Document, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Testimony in case of Peter Branaghin v. Robert Brennan (?)
- Warrants, 1820-1821 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  15 Warrants signed by W.R. Wendell, Justice of the Peace
- Indenture, 1820 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Indenture regarding land between Mayor, Aldermen & Commonality of the City of Schenectady and William Carpenter
- Copy of Certificate, 1821 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Copy of Certificate of Rent due between Enoch Willard and John sanders
- Receipt, 1821 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between H.R. Wendell and James Walker
- Memorandum, 1823 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Mr. John Reed paid all taxes
- Receipt, 1823 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between Aug. Gombault and Mr. Dodge.
- Resolution, 1824 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Resolved that John Sanders will deliver address of Society by Agricultural Society of Schenectady.
- Court Document, 1825 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Document in case of James Fergusan v. H.R. Wendell.
- Receipt, 1825 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between H.R. Wendell and C.A. Breton.
- Receipt, 1826 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Proceedings, 1828 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Lt. Col. Yates' solicitation of alleged charges -- 14th Division New York Light Infantry Order.
- Resolution, 1828 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Resolved that Henry Wendell appointed delegate to Republican State Convention by the Electors of the City and County of Schenectady.
- Letter, 1829 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Letter to Richard Dage from Michael Plantz regarding found wagon
- Warrant, 1829 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Warrant for assault by William Howe upon Henry Cato
- Receipts, 1830-1831 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipts of the Schenectady Lancasterian School.
- Letter, 1830 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Letter to Isaac Howe, Esq. from Solomon Brown regarding order to get mail
- Receipt, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between H.R. Wendell and John J. Yates.
- Subpoena, 1834 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Subpoena in case of Henry R. Wendell v. Harmon Van Schaick
- Deposition, 1836 September (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Deposition of Lemuel D. Sabin regarding injury to Henry R. Wendell's hand.
- Declaration, 1837 January (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Declaration in case of Peter Smith v. Henry R. Wendell
- Receipt, 1837 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between Samuel Matthews and Slyck Ouderkemp
- Receipt, 1837 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt for books between H.B. Stryker and Peter Sanders
- Receipt, 1837 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between H.R. Wendell and J.P. Beekly
- Subpoenas, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Subpoenas regarding trespass in the case of John Brown v. Mohawk & Hudson Railroad Company
- Letter, 1838 September 10 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Letter to Capt. H.R. Wendell from James Teller regarding his resumption of his business.
- Letter, 1844 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Letter to H.R. Wendell from Schenectady Bank regarding amount due
- Receipt, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between H.R. Wendell and District Trustees.
- Receipt, 1845 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between Trustees for School District No. 1 and Jacob Clute
- Receipt, 1846 September 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between Trustees of School District No. 1 and Agnese Wendell
- Receipt, 1847 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between District No. 1 Schenectady and William F. Bolles.
- Receipt, 1847 August 3 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between District and Thomas Reed
- Letter, 1851 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Letter to H.R. Wendell from Alex Holland, Treasurer of Union College, regarding removal of wall at Union College
- Receipt, 1852 June 5 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Receipt between Miss Wendell and George Ohlen
- Receipts, 1730-1849 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  2 receipts from 1730s, 6 receipts from 1740s, 23 receipts from 1750s, 8 receipts from the 1760s, 7 receipts from the 1770s, 8 receipts from the 1780s, 6 receipts from the 1790s, 7 receipts from the 1800s, 9 receipts from the 1810s, 5 receipts from the 1820s, 2 receipts from 1830s, and 1 receipts from the 1840s. Names of payers that are frequently seen are H.R. Wendell, John Sanders, John Empie, Peter Sanders and Jacob Glen. Many of the receipts involve rides on "batoes", wood/timber deliveries, and some sort of payment for militia service.
- Albany County Documents, 1785-1791 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Includes 3 promissory notes and one letter: 1785 promise by Stephen Holley of St. Coin (?), Albany County to pay Jared Lane; 1789 promise by Joseph Hagar to pay Peter Hager of Schoarey, NY; 1785 promise by Ephraim Griswold of Scaughtecoot(?), Albany County, to pay Col. Anthony Hoffman of Rhynebeck, Dutchess County; and 1791 letter from Jacob Zimmer about parcel of land (Schohary).
- Schenectady Schools, 1799-1848 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Folder includes Memorandum forming a Board of Supervisors for Schools in Albany (Schenectady, 1799); Weekly, Quarter Rolls and Attendance Reports for District No. 1, 3rd and 4th Ward of the City of Schenectady; Library book conditions; Tuition due Union College; petitions from different wards requesting a closer school or transportation funds; teachers' payments; subscription for new building; Reports to the Town Superintendents of Common Schools
- Letters, 1820-29 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  25 Letters from D. Boyd, Cashier of Mohawk Bank to Richard Dodge, Esq. These letters deal with early 19th century banking practices and issues -- difficulties of accepting notes; types of money offered; gold and silver issues; paper money from various counties; counterfeit money
- Notice, 1830 April 20 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  A notice sent to H.R. Wendell of Schenectady by D. Boyd, notary at the Mohawk Bank, that a note of Peter C. and Cornelius Tymesen endorsed by H.R. Wendell was protested for non-payment.
- Shares, 1852 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Schenectady and Duanesburgh Plank Road Company certfies that William W. Duane is entitled to 12 shares of stock
- Petition, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Petition to Members of the Council of Appointment regarding the appointment of Andrew Cowan as inspector
- Act, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Act to Fortify town of Schenectady
- Return of Votes, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Voting returns for Supervisor, Town Clerk, Assessors
- True Estimate, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  True Estimate by the Assessors of the City of Schenectady
- List, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  List of Names now in Prince Town Discluded off the Tasel (?) List of the City of Schenectady
- Act, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Act to enforce part of an Act entitled An Act for Raising 50 pounds in the Township of Schenectady
- List, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Undated list of residents of Schenectady with a number of pounds after their names
- Notice of Meeting, April 28 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Notice of an annual meeting for the election of officers for District No. 1, 3rd and 4th Ward of City of Schenectady signed by M. Kendell, Trustee for District
- Schenectady Patent, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Copy of the boundaries of the Schenectady Patent
- List of Votes, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  List of votes for Governor (Dewitt Clinton received 26 votes) and For Assembly
- Receipt, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Receipt between Alexander Stouck and Peter Sanders
- List of Names, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  List is as follows: Abraham Fonda; Christofer Yates; Isaac Vrooman; Albert Mabie; John Empey; Abraham Switts; Cornelis D. Volgen; Henry van Driesen; Cornelis Van Dyck; John Peck; Cornelis Van Slyck
- Account, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Account of Henry R. Wendell
- Monthly Bill, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Monthly bill of District No. 1, 3rd and 4th Ward of City of Schenectady to Henry R. Wendell
- Petition, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Petition for new town of Glenville between Legislature of the State of New York and Freeholders and Electors on the North side of the Mohawk River
- Receipt, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Receipt between H.R. Wendell and M. Trotter
- Receipts - Dutch, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  receipts between Abraham Wempel/Ephriam Smith and Jacobus Van Slyck/Stin Van Dirk
- Draft Proposal - Dutch, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Proposal to supply a minister in place of Rev. Thomas Brower for the Dutch Church at Schenectady
- Petition, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Petition to Judge and Adjutant Justices of the Court Of Common Pleas from John Sanders for a Ferry